Jerome-Alexis Chevalier

PH. D. IN MACHINE LEARNING

17. rue de Gassendi. 75017 Paris

□ +33 (0)6 65 64 02 78 | **□** jerome-alexis.chevalier@inria.fr | **□** ja-che

Summary.

I recently obtained a PhD in machine learning working on the statistical control of sparse models in high dimension with application in neuro-imaging. Earlier, I worked in quantitative finance for more than two years and this is how I first learnt about machine learning. Quickly, I decided to specialize in machine learning since I am passionate by probability, statistics and coding. Now, I am looking for a position where I can contribute to "real-world" projects that require an expertise in machine learning solutions.

Education

Inria Paris-Saclay and Telecom ParisTech

Paris

PhD Candidate: Statistical Control of Sparse Models in High Dimension

2017 - 2021

- · Worked on several models for high dimensional inference (Desparsified Lasso, Multi-Split, Corrected Ridge, Residual Bootstrap)
- Worked on clustering and ensembling techniques suited for statistical inference
- Developed an algorithm (Ensemble of Clustered Desparsified Lasso) adapted for the statistical inference on neuro-imaging problems
- Developed a Python package for high dimensional inference: HiDimStat available at https://ja-che.github.io/hidimstat/
- · Compared algorithms using several neuro-imaging datasets (HCP, IBC, Haxby, Oasis, Neurovault)
- Wrote several research articles in English for machine learning conferences and journals

Universite Paris Diderot, Paris 7

Paris

MASTER OF SCIENCE: STATISTICS, PROBABILITY AND DATA SCIENCE (M2MO, EX-DEA LAURE ELIE)

2016 - 2017

• Machine Learning, Datamining, Probability, Statistics, Stochastic Calculus, Python, C++

Essec Busisness School Paris

Advanced Master: Financial Techniques 2013 - 2014

ENSEIRB-MATMECA

Bordeaux

MASTER OF ENGINEERING: MATHEMATICAL MODELING AND MECHANICS 2010 - 2013

 Lycee Michel Montaigne
 Bordeaux

 PREPARATORY CLASS: MATHEMATICS AND PHYSICS
 2008 - 2010

Publications

MICCAI 2018: Chevalier, J.A., Salmon, J., Thirion, B.: Statistical inference with ensemble of clustered desparsified lasso

IPMI 2019: Chevalier, J.A., Nguyen, B., Thirion, B.: ECKO: Ensemble of clustered knockoffs for robust multivariate inference on MRI data

ICML 2020: Nguyen, B., Chevalier, J.A., Thirion, B., Arlot, S.: Aggregation of Multiple Knockoffs

NeurIPS 2020: Chevalier, Gramfort, Salmon, Thirion: Statistical control for spatio-temporal MEG/EEG source imaging with d-MTLasso **NeuroImage Journal 2021:** Chevalier, Nguyen, Varoquaux, Salmon, Thirion: Decoding with confidence: Statistical control on decoder maps **Submitted to a statistical journal:** Chevalier, Nguyen, Thirion, Salmon: Spatially relaxed inference on high-dimensional linear models

Experience

Inria Paris-Saclay Paris

PHD CANDIDATE: STATISTICAL CONTROL OF SPARSE MODELS IN HIGH DIMENSION

Sep. 2018 - Sep. 2019

• Coding mission: contributed to Nilearn and Nistats machine learning libraries for neuro-imaging in Python

Amundi Alternative Investments

London

QUANTITATIVE ANALYST IN ALTERNATIVE INVESTMENTS

Aug. 2015 - Aug. 2016

Nov. 2014 - Jun. 2015

- Developed and maintained quantitative tools to optimize the fund selection
- · Contributed to the monthly allocation strategy outlooks working closely with three teams (Equity, Fixed Income, Macro)

BNP Paribas Investments Partners - THEAM

Paris

• Managed a range of CPPI lifecycle funds (AuM Eur 1 billion)

· Implemented the investment process including the risky asset allocation and the interest rate hedging

Oddo & Cie - Oddo Asset Management

Paris

QUANTITATIVE INVESTMENT ANALYST

Apr. 2014 - Oct. 2014

· Built investment style indexes and smart beta strategies to monitor market trends and develop new funds

Skills.

FUND MANAGER

Languages: French (native), English (fluent), Spanish (intermediate)

Programming languages and Softwares: Python (Scikit-Learn, Scipy, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn), R, C++, Latex, Git, Atom